<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael Tecourt</title>
    <description>Coding, american football, and very serious thoughts. Because in France, having an opinion counts more than doing something about it.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:13:50 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:13:50 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Service Discovery and the forgotten URNs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I like using Spring Boot / Cloud a lot. I won’t dig too much into it, it’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/java-tools-and-technologies-landscape-2016-trends&quot;&gt;2016&lt;/a&gt; 
and unless you’ve been living under a rock, it has become everything we all expected from Java EE for the last dozen years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I’m currently working on adding service discovery to my customer’s bunch of micro-services, 
and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cloud.spring.io/spring-cloud-netflix/spring-cloud-netflix.html#_service_discovery_eureka_clients&quot;&gt;Eureka&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;http://cloud.spring.io/spring-cloud-netflix/spring-cloud-netflix.html#spring-cloud-feign&quot;&gt;Feign&lt;/a&gt; integration is great.&lt;br /&gt;
For a while I was wondering why the Spring team did not implement “HTTP Repositories” in &lt;a href=&quot;http://projects.spring.io/spring-data/&quot;&gt;spring-data&lt;/a&gt;, 
but I guess they prefered working with Feign instead of reiventing the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only grief would be a meaningless implementation detail, in the way that the service name/url is implemented :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a service name must be provided for each client interface. By default, Eureka transparently provides the corresponding URL(s) associated with that service name&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;you can override the service discovery by providing directly the service URL (useful for testing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are two separate fields on the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;@FeignClient&lt;/code&gt; annotation :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-java highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;/** 
      * In this case, Feign will use directly the URL 
      * instead of resolving the service named &quot;myservice&quot; with Eureka 
      */&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;@FeignClient&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;myservice&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;https://myservice.api.example.com&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;MyServiceClient&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either a name or an address ? sounds familiar ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;uri--urn-or-url&quot;&gt;URI = URN or URL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A name or an address, that’s exactly what a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Identifier#Relationship_between_URIs.2C_URLs.2C_and_URNs&quot;&gt;URI&lt;/a&gt; is :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Locator&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt; : Location (address)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_Resource_Name&quot;&gt;URN&lt;/a&gt; : Name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And how to use a URN ? with some kind of resolver, where Eureka fits the bill as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/5476121/using-dns-as-a-urn-resolver&quot;&gt;non-standard&lt;/a&gt; implementation :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A URN resolver is responsible for initiating and sequencing the queries that 
ultimately lead to a full resolution (translation) of a URN name or a “resolution request”, 
e.g., a request for translation of a URN name into a URL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing here forbids some client side load-balancing : 1 URN -&amp;gt; different URLs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could have been the day when everybody stopped googling “&lt;em&gt;what’s the difference between URI and URL&lt;/em&gt;”, 
because nobody remembers what an abstract concept is before seeing a live example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-java highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;/** Use the service name with a URN. Yup, it&#39;s a valid URI. */&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;@FeignClient&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;uri&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;urn:my-enterprise:myservice&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;MyServiceDiscoveryClient&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-java highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;cm&quot;&gt;/** Use the service location with a URL. Still a valid URI. */&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nd&quot;&gt;@FeignClient&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;uri&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;https://myservice.api.example.com&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;MyDumbClient&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poor URNs that never really worked out. It would have been cool to give new life to that unpopular internet standard.&lt;br /&gt;
The only time I saw URNs in action was when putting together &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_Assertion_Markup_Language&quot;&gt;SAML&lt;/a&gt; single sign-on : few success outside the overly complicated, XML-driven enterprise world.&lt;br /&gt;
Some governments agencies use URNs as unique identifiers, not very popular outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;URNs and service discovery/client side load balancing made a lot of sense to me.&lt;br /&gt;
A lot more sense than &lt;a href=&quot;https://spring.io/guides/gs/rest-hateoas/&quot;&gt;inserting links that clients can’t browse in API responses&lt;/a&gt; (which most believe to be HATEOAS) : 
a waste of time when doing RPC over HTTP (which most believe to be REST)… but I’ll leave that for another blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/16/service-discovery-and-the-forgotten-urn.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/16/service-discovery-and-the-forgotten-urn.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Overcoming Procrastination</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For a while I’ve been telling myself I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; start writing what’s on my mind about coding, 
and (american) football, and whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like anything you tell yourself that you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; do… well you save it for later.&lt;br /&gt;
One of my arguments against my own motivation was that I had too many stuff on my mind, 
and finding where to start is already too much of a challenge for today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because life is full of irony, I’ve been bragging for the last few years that I had developed 
a technique to overcome procrastination (sounds a lot like a motivational speaker, which I’m definitely not).&lt;br /&gt;
Isn’t it the perfect subject to start a blog I’ve kicked aside for a year ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;understanding-the-cause&quot;&gt;Understanding the cause&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Procrastination is not really a thing, just like laziness.&lt;br /&gt;
Both are just words that put a judgement on symptoms, “not doing something”, instead of understanding &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; you “don’t do it”.&lt;br /&gt;
In my case, I found out that I had lofty expectations for the stuff I was procrastinating about.&lt;br /&gt;
I want that thing done so perfectly it becomes a daunting task, I’m overwhelmed.&lt;br /&gt;
The exact thought that flashes through my head when I give up on a task is in fact : &lt;em&gt;This is too much for today&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
I can’t speak for everyone, but procrastination doesn’t come when I don’t care, 
it often comes when I ask myself too much at once. 
Speaking in terms of “deadly sins”, the cause of procrastination would not be laziness, it would be vanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-solution--lowering-the-bar&quot;&gt;The solution : lowering the bar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to “kick my own butt” brought poor results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that has worked so far is &lt;em&gt;lowering the bar&lt;/em&gt; : all you need is too break down your huge task into something smaller.&lt;br /&gt;
Leave your pride aside, you won’t do it well at first. Winning ugly is better than not showing up for the game.&lt;br /&gt;
The most important thing is to get &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; done, event something that may seem insignificant.&lt;br /&gt;
In fact, that &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; can be as small as the bare minimum you can do before the sun sets :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you have to write a letter to appeal a parking ticket (never happened to me), 
just set your objective for today as low as “pulling a sheet of paper and writing my name on it”.  Just that. Once you’ve done it, you can go to sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you have to write up an essay, just ask yourself to create a blank Word file, and save it with a decent file name. Just that. Once you’ve done it, you can go to sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you have to clean up your windows, just ask yourself to clean one window pane in your room. Just that. Once you’ve done it, you can go to sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you have to fix some old code at work, just ask yourself to get &lt;em&gt;one line&lt;/em&gt; fixed before lunch. Just that. Once you’ve done it, you can go to lunch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me two things can happen :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get so pumped up that I actually got &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; started that I finish it all at once&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m actually really tired / have something else to do, 
but my brain remembers that I actually started something, 
and the next morning it’s naturally on my mind when I wake up. Since I already started, there is no “entry ticket” anymore, I can get going fast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is nothing new to software developers working in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Agile_software_development&quot;&gt;agile&lt;/a&gt; environments.&lt;br /&gt;
When you break down a big task into small pieces, each small success fuels your hunger for more success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like in most things in life, all you need is to make that one tiny little step, and put all your heart into it. Momentum does the rest.&lt;br /&gt;
My father used to tell me that there is a lot more difference between zero and one, than between one and a million, 
because you can multiply zero with everything you want it’s still 0 (yup, he is the motivational speaker of the family).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal stuff aside, here it is, I got started with my tiny little step, my low hanging fruit, the easiest blog post I could figure out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See ? Now that I have it all figured out with majestuous modesty, I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; proceed to write something highly impressive… but it would be too much for today :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/14/overcoming-procrastination.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2016/07/14/overcoming-procrastination.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mobile apps madness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I often hear colleagues and family speak about how big bad internet companies collect their data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, I find it highly confusing that these same persons are the ones who blindly give permissions to mobile apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s answer the following questions together :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Would you install an application to access your bank accounts on your desktop/laptop computer, instead of using your browser ?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Would you give it full access over your files and hardware, for features that will &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; work offline anyway ?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Even if &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; these features can already be accessed from a website…&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;in a device-friendly user interface ?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;without giving up any access to your private data ?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;without taking overpriced diskspace on your overpriced iPhone ?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-phrase-this-another-way--are-you-nuts-&quot;&gt;Let’s phrase this another way : Are you nuts ?!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why bring all that nonsense to your mobile phone, which is just a small touch-based computer loaded with private data ? &lt;br /&gt;
Does that cool looking icon in the app store really makes you lose your mind ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;but-typing-addresses-is-boring&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“But typing addresses is boring”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just put the mobile site in your favorites, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnet.com/how-to/adding-one-touch-bookmarks-to-your-androids-home-screen/&quot;&gt;add a shortcut icon to your homescreen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a rule of thumb, do not install an application unless it provides irreplaceable offline features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such features may be :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;using a GPS for navigation - NOT localization, ordering your cab can be achieved through a browser !&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;stuff with advanced graphics : games, sketching, video editing…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;stuff to read offline : books, courses, music/video apps with offline mode…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;professional tooling : payment, docs, spreadsheets…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exception to the offline rule is when you need to get notified (push) in real time : messaging, traffic alerts…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you obviously &lt;strong&gt;don’t&lt;/strong&gt; need to install apps for :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Checking your bank account -&amp;gt; website !&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social networks -&amp;gt; website !&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ordering a pizza -&amp;gt; website, or *shocker* : phone !&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reading the news -&amp;gt; website or paper !&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shop online -&amp;gt; website !!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anything that was only a website before smartphones -&amp;gt; website !!!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Any promotional offer that requires you to install an app -&amp;gt; just don’t, unless getting spammed makes you feel special&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re probably screwed when it comes to vendors collecting data directly from our operating systems, 
let’s not shoot ourserlves in the foot by opening more doors than necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/25/mobile-apps-madness.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/25/mobile-apps-madness.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First post with Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that’s all I have to say for my first post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/22/first-one.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2015/09/22/first-one.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
